Guide to the Jane Conlon Muller Oral History Collection AIA.012
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Charles J. Hynes (1935 - ), 1991; 1 cassette, 1 master compact disc, 1 access compact disc
  - Charles J. Hynes - 2 December 1991, Dec 2, 1991; cuid690; [00:00 - 10:00] Kings county district attorney Background - family, childhood, where he developed his Irish identity. How he became involved in Irish American activities - protesting hunger strikes, co-founding Irish Solidarity Day.; 1 ma
    [02:35] Do you know what level of education they had?
    [02:45] And do you know how they made a living?
    [03:13] And your grandmother?
    [03:16] How many children did your grandparents have?
    [03:21] And now where was your father born?
    [03:28] Where was your mother born?
    [03:34] What level of education did your father have?
    [03:45] And how did your father make a living?
    [03:51] And your mother?
    [03:54] And how many children?
    [04:01] And where were you born?
    [04:07] And you were raised…?
    [04:12] What is your first recollection of knowing that you were Irish?
    [05:01] Was there any other Irish influence in your life?
    [05:09] Your parents then didn't belong to any Irish American organizations when you were young growing up?
    [05:26] Tell us a little about your military experience.
    [05:44] You said there was no Irish neighborhood experiences growing up?
    [06:01] And what about your religious background?
    [06:10] And you married a woman by the name of…?
    [06:34] And now your children, you have…? And has this Irish influence trickled down to them through the stories that you've told them or Irish involvement that you're in - tell me a little bit about it.
    [07:30] What is the first daughter's name?
    [07:44] Did you ever have a time when you felt you had to defend it [being Irish] growing up? Do you recall when you yourself got active in your Irishness?
    [09:09] What was the focus, merely to protest the hunger strike?
    [09:44] What prompted you to get active and to form this?
    [10:19] Then where did you go from there with your Irish involvement?
    [11:49] Do you think that there's something inside you that draws you to do this that maybe wouldn't be in the being of another political leader that might not be of Irish background, or do you think it's involved with your legal knowledge and professionalism?
    [13:24] Are there other Irish causes that you've been called on to speak out about in recent times?
    [13:52] What about the Joe Doherty situation?
    [14:18] Is there any other Irish-type involvement that you're currently involved in or you just do what comes up when it's necessary?
    [14:33 ] Is there any time in your life or your career where you have felt that someone was prejudiced against you just because you are Irish?
    [15:42] How did you feel?
    [16:38] Do you feel that the Irish have been tagged incorrectly as drunks? What do you think is the reason that they've been so tagged?
    Duration: 18 Minutes. Preservation Note: Side 2 is blank.